Guide to the Paul Strand Photographs of the American Southwest and Mexico
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Paul Strand Photographs of the American Southwest and Mexico
1927-1932
YCAL MSS 882
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
15
photographic prints
Fifteen framed photographic prints of subjects primarily in the American Southwest and Mexico. Also present are two portraits of artist Rebecca Salsbury James.
Strand, Paul, 1890-1976
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Rebecca Salsbury James, 1964.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Paul Strand (1891-1968), American photographer and filmmaker, married to the artist Rebecca Salsbury James from 1922 until 1933.
Scope and Contents
Fifteen framed photographic prints of subjects primarily in the American Southwest and Mexico. Also present are two portraits of artist Rebecca Salsbury James.
Photographers -- United States; New Mexico -- Pictorial works; Southwest, New -- Pictorial works; Mexico -- Pictorial works; Photographic prints; Photographers -- United States -- 20th Century; Strand, Paul, 1890-1976; James, Rebecca Salsbury, 1891-1968 -- Portraits
- Portrait of Rebecca Salsbury James (8 x 10 inches), 1932-1932 (Box 1)
- Tesuque Church, Tesuque Pueblo, New Mexico (4.5 x 3.5 inches), 1930-1930 (Box 1)
- Two horses, Taos, New Mexico (4 x 5 inches), 1930-1930 (Box 1)
- Landscape, Taos, New Mexico (3.5 x 4.5 inches), 1930-1930 (Box 1)
- White horse, Taos, New Mexico (4.5 x 6 inches), 1931-1931 (Box 2)
- Portal, Truchas, New Mexico (6 x 4.5 inches), 1931-1931 (Box 2)
- Ranchos de Taos Church, or La Iglesia de San Francisco de Asis, Ranchos de Taos, New Mexico (4.5 x 6 inches), 1932-1932 (Box 2)
- Ranchos de Taos Church, or La Iglesia de San Francisco de Asis, buttress and houses (6 x 4.5 inches), 1932-1932 (Box 2)
- Landscape near Abiquiú, New Mexico (4.5 x 6 inches), 1931-1931 (Box 2)
- Crucifixion, Tlacochoaya, Oaxaca, Mexico (7.5 x 9.5 inches), 1933-1933 (Box 3)
- Calvario, Pátzcuaro, Mexico (9.5 x 7.5 inches), 1933-1933 (Box 3)
- Cristo, Oaxaca, Mexico (9.5 x 7.5 inches), 1933-1933 (Box 3)
- Man with hoe, Los Remedios, Mexico (6 x 4.5 inches), 1933-1933 (Box 3)
- Cobweb in rain, Georgetown, Maine (9.25 x 7.5 inches), 1927-1927 (Box 4)
- Portrait of Rebecca Salsbury James, Mexico (5.75 x 4.5 inches), 1933-1933 (Box 4)